Preliminary Guide to the Gelman Library Administration records, ca. 1825-2005 RG0119
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Office records, 1994-1997; RG0119 Series 50; 7.5 Linear feet
  - Serials Librarian, 1994-2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Siggins: Subspec Lunches, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sexual Harassment Recognition and Prevention, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Staff Management Group - December 15 SCAN, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Working File: Staff Management Group Retreat, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Standing Committee on Library Education, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Working File: SPEC Exhibits, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Staff Assn. Comm, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Staff Training, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Candidate for Gelman University Library, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - U.L. Search, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - U.L.S, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Working File: University 175th Anniversary, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Working File: Walt Whitman Exhibit, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - WLP Support and Education Network Committee, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Women's Leadership Project, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Workflow Applications in the Image Processing Environment, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Faculty Authors Signing Reception, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Authors Signing Reception, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Employee Hire Form, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Working File: Family Weekend/Open House, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - First Annual Washington Consumer Book and Information Technology Fair, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Foggy Bottom Neighbors, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Friends Annual Gift, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Working File: Friends Dinner, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Working File: Friends Ideas, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Friends: Sample Renewal Letters, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Working File: Annual Report, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Working File: Budget, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Annual Report, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Working File: Annual Report, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Gelman Library Student Advisory Board, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Working File: GW Administrators Briefing, 02/1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - GW: Capital Need Identification, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Gillette Book Signing, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Graphics for Trustee Report, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Events: Gratefully Yours Exhibit, 11/02/1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Government Documents Librarian Policy Studies Specialist, 07/1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Green University Summer Session, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - GWIS, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hank Lutton: Meetings, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Working File: Lance Hidy Event - Spring, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hypertext Symposium, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Working File: Library/Code of Student Conduct, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Library of the Future Background/Text, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Library of the Future Comparative Stats, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Library of the Future Literature, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Library of the Future Stats: Int. Gelman, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Librarian Instruction Librarian, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Library Review for Staff, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Library Update, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Working File: Library Violence/Disaster Planning, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lost in the City, 02/13/1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Working File: Lost in the City Traveling Exhbibitions, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Memorial Requests, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Working File: M.I.S. at Gelman, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Notebook Workshop, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Working File: Open Forum, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Orientation Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Our Other Lives: Creators and Collectors, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Policies to be Reviewed by PPG, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - PPG/Qual. Council, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - PPG Retreat, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Working File: PR Blitz, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Working File: PR/Special Events Position, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Working File: Presentations 3.0 Workshop, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Working File: Presentation Training, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - GW: Presidents Night, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 1993-2000; RG0119 Series 51; 5.5 Linear feet (Box 3, Box 2, Box 1)
  This series includes files and correspondence of the University Librarian. They range in date from 1993-2000.
  Formerly ACC#1033
- Publication, 1988-2001; RG0119 Series 52; 3 Linear feet
  This series includes "Connect" - publication of the Gelman Library from 1988-2001. There is also one copy of Gelman Exposed Circa 2001 and a copy of "Vision" GW library publication from Winter 2013-2014.
  Formerly ACC#407
- Office files, 1988-2005; RG0119 Series 53; 6 Linear feet
  These office files belonged to University Librarian Jack Siggins. Files include Faculty Senate records, library budgets, financial reports, and newsletters. They range in date from 1988-2005. They were transfered to the University Archives in 2006.
- Andrea Stewart records, 1987-2005; 2003-2005; RG0119 Series 54; 15 Linear Feet (Box UP0010, Box UP0012, Box UP0009, Box UP0007, Box UP0008, Box UP0011, Box UP0006, Box UP0005, Box UP0003, Box UP0001, Box UP0002, Box UP0004, Box UP0013)
  Arrangement
  These records are not yet processed and no series have been determined. The box inventory appears to be a list of the titles of binders. The binders remain in original order with orginal titles.
  Box level inventory
  All this data comes from description pages attached to the outside of the box. We can presume these descriptions were prepared by Andrea Stewart.
  Box 1: Learning Organization; Banner/Alumni Development Gift Journal 2004-2005; Admin 2004; Orientation/Library Information; GW 2004; LAMA Leadership Development Committee
  Box 2: Development Group 2004; Development-Annual Fund 2003-2004 & 2004-2005; Alternative Academic Calendar 1 of 3; Alternative Academic Schedule 200 2 of 3; Alternative Academic Calendar 3 of 3; LibQUAL+ Spring 2003
  Box 3: Admin 2002; Admin Binder 2003; CHRON 2003; Academic Excellence 2003; Budget June 2002
  Box 4: Development Reports 2005; ASPP Fall 2001-Spring 2005; Admin 2005; Development Letters 2005; Friends of GW Libraries 2005; Oracle Training; Customer Service Workshop
  Box 5: User Survey 1997; ALA Binder 2003-2004; Annual Report 2003; ASPP Fall 1998-Spring 2001; The Gelman Library System Annual Report 2003-2004; ASSESS 2003; 1987 User Survey
  Box 6: 1994 User Survey Book 1; 1994 User Survey Book II; 1994 User Survey Book III; 1994 User Survey Book IV
  Box 7: Human Resources Binder FY 2000; Council of Librarians Files from June 30, 1992 and Before; Strategic Planning Group FY 1999; Statstics Oline Project 2002; Friends 2004; Strategic Planning Group FY 2000-FY 2002; Human Resources Binder FY 2001
  Box 8: banner/Alumni Development Gift Journal FY 2001-2003; Library Journal; CHRON 2004; LTF4; Development Group February 1, 2001 to June 2, 2003; The Gelman Library System Annual Report 2202-2003; The Gelman Library System Annual Report 2001-2002; Annual Report 2002-2001
  Box 9: Develpment Group June 2, 2003 to December 2003; User Survey 1990; Donor Database Users Group 2002; Goal II Stat. Plan 2002-2005; SMG 2003-2004
  Box 10: JAS-Credenza Notes Nov. 2002-June 2006; ALA CPE Focus on Library Support June 2003; SPACE Ja. 1999-[2005]; ASSESS 2001
  Box 11 (added later): Contains 1 folder with the following contents: 1) Program for the acceptance of the Gilbert Stuart Portrait (1/28/1983) 2) Gelman Tenth Anniversary Dinner at Cosmos Club (3/30/1984) 3) Reception for Sharon Rogers, University Librarian (7/12/1984) 4) Tenth Anniversary of Gelman Library Building (3/9/1984)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series 54 is closed for 50 years from date of record creation.
- Eckles Library records, 1998-2005; RG0119 Series 55; .5 Linear Feet
  This series contains material relating to the Eckles library and the Mount Vernon campus.
  - Annual reports and ephemera about the Mount Vernon Campus, 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - Eckles Memorial Library Brochures (Box 1)
- Andrea Stewart and Jack Siggins records, 1973-2012; 1985-2012; RG0119 Series 56
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  These files were accessioned upon the clean-out of filing cabinets previously belonging to Andrea Stewart and Jack Siggins, which had been moved to a storage room. Part of accession 2016-002.
  Biographical / Historical
  During the time period covered by these files, Andrea Stewart served as the Assistant University Librarian for Administration and Human Resources (2000-2003) and the Associate University Librarian for Administration, Human Resources and Development (2003-2012) under University Librarian Jack Siggins.
  Separated Materials
- Gelman library construction binders and plans, 2003-2014; RG0119 Series 57; 6 linear feet
  - Gelman 3rd floor renovation (Tube 1)
  - Gelman third floor ceiling and floor plan, 2005 (Tube 2)
  - Lower Level Compact Shelving Proposal, 1990 (Tube 3)
  - Starbucks Tenant Space Preparation, 2004 (Tube 4)
  - Gelman sprinkler plan, 2005 (Tube 5)
  - Gelman lower level thru penthouse, 1991 (Tube 6)
  - Entrance floor renovation (Tube 7)
  - Gelman 3rd floor master plan, 2004 (Tube 8)
  - Virginia campus first floor partition plan, 2004 (Tube 9)
  - Gelman third floor renovations phase 1, 2005 (Tube 10)
  - Gelman 6th and 7th floor renovations, 2001 (Tube 11)
  - Library entrance/2nd floor renovation, 2012 (Tube 12)
  - Gelman 6th and 7th floor renovation, 1998 (Tube 13)
  - Gelman 6th and 7th floor renovation, not for construction, 1998 (Tube 14)
  - System and technology office, 2nd floor 100% review, 1997 (Tube 15)
  - Gelman 6th and 7th floor renovation, 1998 (Tube 16)
  - Gelman floor plans, laminated, 2001 (Tube 17)
  - Gelman entrance floor renovation, void, 2012 (Tube 18)
  - System and technology office, 2nd floor, 1997 (Tube 19)
  - Gelman entrance floor renovation, 2012 (Tube 20)
  - Gelman entrance floor renovation, 2012 (Tube 21)
  - Gelman library renovation plans, all floors (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous library records, 1950-2017; Series 58; 7.5 Linear Feet 5 record center cartons
  Miscellaneous unprocessed library records that were in the processing room when the new university archivistarrived in 2015, or were randomly dropped off between 2015 and 2017. Most have no clear provenance.
  Accession 2017-046
  The administrative records in box 5 may contain confidential employee information and should be reviewed before being provided to researchers.
  - Unsorted Gelman Library publications and printed materials, circa 1990-circa 2010 (Box 1)
  - Kiev collection guides, 2003-2010 (Box 2)
  - Library staff photographs, event recordings, guest books, the photograph book produced for Steven Knapp's farewell, library staff cookbook, etc., circa 1985-2017 (Box 3)
  - Library reports, 1950-1980; Library brochures and printed materials, circa 1973-1980 (Box 4)
  - University Librarian briefing binder, 2013; miscellaneous administration files (annual reports, strategic planning, etc.), circa 2000-2006, circa 2000-2013 (Box 5)
    The administrative files in this box may contain confidential employee data and should be reviewed by an archivist prior to release.
  - Ari Kiev Correspondence, 2002-2012; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Box 6 is restricted for 25 years from date of record creation.
  - Kiev - internal staff correspondence, 2002-2003; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Endowment documentation, 1996-1999; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Japan Economic Institute Library, 2000-2001; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Teamsters, 2007-2011; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Corcoran archives, gift agreement and negotiations, 2010-2016; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - Gelman renovation plans, 2010; Series 58 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Proclamation - Melvin Gelman Library Day, 2002 May 2 (Box 7)
    In 2002, the mayor of DC proclaimed May 2, 2002 as Melvin Gelman Library Day. The Gelman Library had been working to strengthen its African American resources, and the day was chosen in memory of the 34th anniversary of the assissination of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.